lecture
sort out
just wish to renew i received server and
i'm going to give you
part of her weight you can catch up to
it you want to stick with the character
of
from before
and i'm gonna go
effective active to hear
they should be the last time we switch
servers for
piracy
problems i hope
i'll go ahead and
walk you're setting up tents or
so here i started tags or
i mean he wakes up from the mac here
because we're running low on computers
and i might even bring in some work
appears in case we have a people person
throughout the semester
inside a child's illa
last time we did attach
aliyev free no dress sinatra used this
address appear
and see if you attach
research
tools
sitcom an h
they could still use their free node
service if you want backed by channel
if there's nobody on their you'll be
creating it is the first user
it but if you want to private grandma
acdsee com
then you can use for notice when what
only work if you're on the secom
workstation in the classroom
for secom specific lopped off
anything else is going to be a different
networking will not be able to so
when we work on this i received
that stuff stays within sight of secom
so there will be rain people from the
outside world something in
so that has to research tools to combine
h
not connected up
and i'm using a lot of affection ccom
sold to you
and
pound u_n_ age research
tools like me spaces
and i see it to you in there
secure more jumping in
i'm gonna stick showing you the way to
set up in the notes visit school called
cajun which is an instant messenger
client that works on windows clinics and
mac
it supports i received a lot to
messenger google chat
awesome stuff
dats noted by some people in the past i
don't always known as the i_o_c_ during
plots if i'm working on pa stuff
if you really want response for me is
opposed to someone else in the class
when you posted heritage and he'll let
me know if you look at the screen
because it would be great
willful different places at the same
time
the for today
i've got
notes online
if you go and look at b
research tools webpage i've set up
the blackboard page has a link to it
blackboard i'll post links but all the
material will be on this web page so
that you know it for some reason
blackboard
your password or playing nicely or if
you want to share to someone else you
can see in this link in public
today's lecture notes as with the of our
election so far still in draft form
quiet lecturers one three four
audio files available
oven trying to keep up with those
and lecture five has got
notes initiative all forms of it but i'm
not you can follow along
and if you're having trouble copying
typing in what we do today
you can you a copy paste instead of just
typing like we have this trouble last
time with deal longer one
being trouble about that one look like
much like an hour again
people who haven't been here before
on that same web page
there is only to vmware even to virtual
machines you click on that
this is where
called a virtual machines that
bogdan live
and you can download
vote for the m_v_k_ and the imax
jumping into
lecture notes
now let me show you guys are blocking
the weeds serene doing like piracy and
tvs
move they make directories
i want to show you guys and tools that
you can use right away
and we're trying to little bit of
this each class if i can
wouldn't do that
so you can have some you can use it to
me deeply
this is one that uh... the person who's
responsible for me doing this to sing
for band
talked me into using up bookmarking
service called
delicious
near idea of
bookmarking services that
you may be using mobile computers
all of you are in this room
you don't have the same accounts
you know is a warning to conserve and
all of your files on location or not the
same files at your
plot top your home machines
and if you go out elsewhere
any different peer your book more
conflict that don't follow you
but if he is one of the services you can
have things like your bookmarks
such that you are going to reach
computer and you have access to shame
bookmarks with delicious you can make
them public or keep it private
so this way if you want to you can
actually
create bookmarks other people can see so
as you do your research people can
follow along with your doing
that's great quiet i went through in a
warning before you go into this
and the stubble of her morning one issue
don't use the same
password as he is on your other accounts
amateur you probably next time how to
use a firm called ke pass acts
to keep all of your passwords encrypting
and will help you generate crazy looking
passwords that are super sick here
so for now you've gotta create new
password magnificent remember always
password but
please do not use your cheek on password
on this trip cancer standoff
use a different password
and we give you a quick
at jumping straight delicious
there's lots and lots of users
up on the front page will be for about
top
hits of people's bookmarks if you want
to see what people are bookmarking a lot
of
is that going on
each user
has a page for their bookmarks that they
won't take a look at mine
my username
is go too far
part goes to the jury
and you can see and hear that you'll see
some of it
the bookmark that i've been making
as i work on things like this clock to
see if he runs a i've been using
audacity to record the classes and at
that
the audio
sixteen or people of bookmark that's
that's pretty popular
here's notes on our aside five course
for instance i pi tight on library for
science
mappings topics at our center
this service has some club tags
so for every bookmark you can add tags
to particular entry
order out of this chaos if you just had
a pile of bookmarks
detract from football there is not the
typical strategy that people use
when they give bookmarking in a browser
but here you can just add whatever tax
you want to itself arrived after the
event id
doxie because if there's lots of links
for that
podcasting
podcast
tutorials
and research tools research tool to
someone using
rumblings relate to this course
and you can then go and put on research
tool
you see all the tags
all the items that i attacked research
tools
some of them may not seem like they're
very important yet to you because i've
got things that are going on in my head
that all went to bring in the course
but some of the might be interesting if
you go along
so there's lots of interesting stuff in
there
anticipated service where you can then
hooked into this for me chair computers
and you can add it up again
to firefox
and i eat there's probably other
brothers to you
we actually have gotten sick though
great into delicious so i've got these
three buttons up here's firefox
if i had this button
you get a dialog box something like this
where i can bookmark something i can add
tags and
pick something more interesting
slashdot
or you're getting splash diet use for
nerds
will hit tag
and hopefully in a few seconds you'll
see some recommendations pop up as it's
working
so now it's gone off found some
recommend tags
footed my tags and said these are the
ones that fit well
it for protection of the people in
cities once worked well
to give you some hints as to you
how you might want to organize your
material
now you can also had some comments
there's a really
interesting feature that i first thought
was
so here
ablinkin why delicious tag cloud
when the thing that i first thought was
pretty pointless
here's all the tags in the point is
cheating size based on
how many times i've done how frequently
come recent
the cool thing about this is it actually
to go through my tags or generate them
and he tries to give you a sense of
what's
important to me
the areas around here and you look at
their tag cloud
you can see
sobai steer the biggest one honors
deepwater horizon so that was a big
thing for my world
recently
you can see pipeline
equity research tools here is certain to
grow that figure
egg is your sense of the things that i'm
paying about yeah i asked
missus chip tracking
benefiting from my research
in his her to see
what's important to a person and a quick
glance few create your own bushes thing
you can then church type of people and
they can get a sense of your recent
ideas that you go
that mazzola getting all the details of
interaction
delicious it's free
there are also lots of of
bookmarking services out there
you can also used up choir sing can set
up our box or chrome has won the auction
i'd believe i he probably does to you
i put in some whites in the course notes
for
a list of social bookmarking websites
at the paris in a browser synchronizes
sway as you move through the world of
long to have connection to you
the internet you can get access to that
data that you're working with
super portents
don't use a service that will let you
back up your data delicious have an
export link
use it
saved at file somewhere else because it
to adjust to the company disappears
whoever owns them
decides to kill the service your jamie
just disappear
the cloud service for example dot that
we all thought that young who's going to
be around for a long time
yahoo put itself up for sale last week
huge internet company there in the
number one surgeon for a long time and
now they're saying hey wait
but sell off a lot of our stopped me
will shut down some services and
all of you count on it
the careful across services and make
sure the backup
but they're fun
do something right away example for the
day
now let's jump into
actually using
our virtual machine in certain to
explore some data put together a sample
data set
you've got decide today to have you guys
waterson samples and start to see how to
look at data and figure out
what is it and what can i do with it
so let's go ahead
regret this dataset but don't use this
link break here return from a terminal
i'm gonna try and push you guys into
using
more command line stuff that you
probably used to some normal you just
right click the sign-in saved
gotta put that into your windows
environment
not your virtual machine ridiculous
virtual machine
and we're gonna run
this commander here
creeder
a tiny you are out
that points to this really long
u r l two go grab the examples awful
o'clock website
pulling up the virtual machine
may play
diem worked with the writing that's okay
they will in a moment
if you don't know
using them how corrupt happier had
you've memorized the yet that's ok
username is research tools
the password is an exclamation point
the lower case letter are
she hasn
the numbers
two zero one one
story here
and in the lower case letters v_ as in
victor hernandez and mary
glad she's a thirty two-bit operating
system
that was tough one
henry really great to use a sixty
four-bit offering some personal things
are going to do with large files but
prefer class
i want to talk with someone you
everything would work for
if we try to to work with files for them
three or four gigabytes will hit erica
thing thank you
to be a bites
but for this court we're not going to
work with files update
if we're building at the end of going
take out four production his i would try
to make it sixty four-bit
with high pulling together and that
after of course is done
to do the same exact stuff and work
through all the bugs of sixty four-bit
stuff
not everything built for correctly right
now
we're still working through some of the
issues of getting all the software
available
the first thing to do you
if we're gonna want to hear is also nice
little link
i don't have any items in here
there's no terminal for easy use
you can go an application to test a res
and get yourself a terminal
what we wanted to add that appear so
it's just one click
sona right-click
on the stop handlebar
at the panel
and a_b_c_ sort of
springs with the board on top of
something
the second one is application launcher
this is gonna
take items from application launcher and
put them up here so that we can get to
them quickly
you briefly just elise assortment of
quick
and what we want to under excess urease
and i have you had to when the list for
later in the class if we get to it
and that will be community max
at the bottom
and you'll see a little
with old something through it
on a purple circle
appear there
and he scroll down
if the terminal
click ad
on maternal
to go back
so it goes to you miss best part if you
go to top
there's this little trying on the left
that sort of uh... expands
this region expand that
and then scroll down to terminal and
actor answering your have
this will make a right on and in this
weird p
so this is a layer of your own what
to use those when you know
and then add theme acts and then
philosophy a terminal down below
that's cool down
tonight heavy you right there
and scroll down will be a terminal
so what you don't like that
in quick close the ad panels
and we're going to start
start terminal
i'm going to go back and grab
that link
pornographic stab you get
right grab this papa doc
they're probably figure that controls
the windows
view copy
back here and
ledu debe de at this time you are all
samples file
and you're ready to enter
in a runoff the server
and kravitz returned all the same time
correct farmer network a little bit here
to go back to your
web browser
you a copy
back there then go and it pays
ideas all
giver the proper menu and kill your
terminal
kickbacks
stern terminal
i think you have to type in their
something up with copy based on your
machine
no we haven't had that
so you have to watch what i picked it up
people
it's control chip to be
so in this terminal it's not just
control the
get back to do control shifty
as in victor
control c talk a lot of uses it in
terminal
bridge hijacked
gifford lectures shift on there
and go for it to say hi and the chat
room
i'll read out later
so it's going to take a look at this
probably just download it
you know a special
it's kind of annoying to have been rap
so i can to make my terminal
so i have this file here
on the swine
examples
doesn't eleven oh nine thirteen
i need to usually wait
fortieth year to get month through
tuesday
so you can see that a lot with me
it's always good to have a lot of
uncertainty
turned around
it's a little confusing here because we
have a plot one download they had to
have a different name
and debbie can't just look at the u r l
and grabbed than a minute prosecutor who
are reading this
so we can do a andy
examples
now i have had their artist heike
akki tax
tab
and that completes
as best he can what's going on
a see how it got stuck
there's two example thingies
in this directors as an example dash and
are here this is the one we have
and there's a examples dot desktop
so they can't figure out which one of
those who want
if you hit tab
of more times it'll show you what he
thinks it could be
enemies you typed one more character to
get past itself without the dash
it now will know
that we want to the one of the dash in
the year
smith have again you know complain all
the way out
and into that again said samples dash
amor an add on
our extension
keeping the clear
abstentions
harkins they don't change was in the
final but their hands to programs to
what's in that file so we're gonna add
ke a are
easy
member to you
go ahead and do that
now could you ask that cell
you'll notice that color changed
so now it's red
still right there it's still say number
plates
and what this this is is it a part-time
it's the kind of like a zip file fifty
nos for windows it's a file that
contains lots of other files and
directories
so you can be free
scoop of a part of a computer
put into one file past that file around
between people or computers
a lot easier than you can say several
hundred little files and directories
rename it to him to ourselves that the
tar and easy
a lot of tools will for account to on
that extension to help you out
preview completions
wants to see a dot r
to know that there's been a part in
waltham
you usually good
s just we're trying to be clean
you container files anything you can't
gain every single problem random
characters
after about agape doing that you're
gonna go crazy
separate question
our do it not because it changes the
contents but because it's a hence to us
we can take a look at
that with the command called tar
ta or
we can ask for help
if you've ever with dash dash help
and it's going to give you all sorts of
annoying stuff
and you can read it later
or you can type of man
and you get the name page for charged
all the committee c today
you can always try to run the man
command to get more info on it
there's not always a man paid for
everything
remember the kyuki
if you have of uh... man page
you're desperate you can always close
the terminal
so we're gonna take a look at that park
file
it's got some funny options dot lots a
lot of options
says
we're gonna do u so i'm not sure what t
stands for but basically it's filled
with within their
access were going to give it a file
there's a lot of other fancy things you
can do a card doesn't have to do with
actual files
every b_t_u_ act gives you more details
about
what's goin there so the stance
riverboats
tour around the city after the v_
and hit enter
it may be lost both egoistic control c
part way through a few
if you like you don't want to the rest
of the and wait for it to you
go through that are applied nair
but it's a show us that we have a pretty
nice car
type remakes means to me that if you
have a tower
it opens up an expanse just into one
folder
it's pretty mean the people to have a
tar file that just has dropped files
were ever
if it does that i've had times where you
don't think about what to do you want
are something up i love all of your
files
and now you have a mixture of somebody
else's stuff and your stuff and try to
figure out which one belongs to you
and which one came from the star it's me
excellent question
says its tape archive
the second part
would be easy to you
which are in stock
about morning use all the time
this is compressed
with the commander called visa
there's lots of compression programs
but the zip
and use it
are the two main ones that you're gonna
seen here
you'll also see
which is a combination of compression
and
sticking files together
victor comes from the windows world of
things
it's ok it's a lot
useful to you start to continue to talk
so we have uh... coupon
correcting the funds
antar
no different things about proper
missions and dates and times and helping
to organize
also will you work with sits on the
women's side you offer further steps
that a proprietary
winzip or two from
encryption and use formats that are not
publicly available anne cooper
mississippi you only can use from wendy
so
you're forcing your bread to go out and
buy a copy of a bit its
nice to have a compression there but we
have weighed in unix do you
compression and
encryption also if you'd like to do you
and steps as opposed to just in one dr
so now we have
a look and area looks ok
let's unpacked
all these files
of course
city and the
teleport them for hair so when you start
off with that
and he commands
it's going to be
your source clowning
so we need to have the examples dash
without the dot tar dot
easy to which you don't have
and then you have a destination
catherine de est e
this will be
at long haul in with the car dot easy to
on the end
reply when you do you happen to the
following you want to have
the next command greta go ahead and
extract that
acts is the character for extractors
part
except and in the file name
tar actually knows about
the zip anti zip compression
revert to you and use it
you don't have to tell i think specialty
uncompressed that file on the flight was
delayed
enter now i have input maybe dinner for
verbose
so it's gonna be quiet and just work on
it
peccadillos pressuring fidel mode of
multiple gigabyte file annual star
untiring it
you have no idea how far for the follow
you are can get along link to sit there
and wait and hope
singer finish for me
no such file or directory doing
ella special
dual listing tell us that show other
directory
you've missed the rename step
so you need to do it and the of examples
yet tab
now attached
and then the names of the acts
netbackup one character with the
backspace key
dot are
not be easy to you
and i'm doing a listing
so fast that cell again
except as a space between alice
sociology and retreating two that's the
correct
the apparel into your back your claim
that wasn't working
there there's your command to extracted
if that's right santander
and salad
yeah
all the stuff in the notes to respond
actually was able to wipe it up before
class
city tower
t at
the v_
he is the optimal fortunate you're doing
absence on a file sources list
apply all
and however votes uh... he had more visa
gets more votes and then you're bombing
i don't know how many of these you can
tell it's not any more information
depending on the cool sometimes you can
hear a lot
so the next command that we can do this
to start taking a look at what's in
there so we can do
ls dash l
any received
this is the tarp always start out with
and this is the directory of unpack
stuff that tucker
there's a high really nifty commands
paltry
so you can run on the directory three
and it will print out for a
visualization of what's in there
salt expats
and doesn't copy and paste into many
programs both in seizing some funny
characters
leprosy tree
examples
an art timestamp
enter
you get this will graphical
representation of what's in there
had to be colored just like ls were
directories are blue
files that are compressed are ready
things they're just filed with the new
about her weight
things that are marked as execute a ball
are karine
when we have programs the program for
this green yellow color
not really a green it's not really
yellow
worked for me
and there's a killer ones were it's got
to sort of aqui color for
some of the audio files that recognized
why do we have the directory tree
created from our tower
so in the tar
it actually encodes
that directory tree
it isn't just a container you throw
things into it actually keeps the
structure that you create
so if you have a directory trade
tech examples
inadvertent are former called one a
folder called too
here were dark here
and you did over here so some i cant
excel spreadsheet it's going to keep
those folders
and the whole structure that you capture
three strike in the current directory
and just will create this tree attorney
for we are
people often use the tower
command for backups c can back up huge
portions of your computer just ate all
of this whole area
give me one big file that represents all
the data in this portion of my trees my
home directory
these waves just cd and change directory
internet directory and then farther
can you can specify
with a talking a lot that file
you can say tar
access
and you can point to any pac
could be
you could go into my director if you can
find a common xin saying
where
examples
party could be anywhere
so as long as you
you know we're not tar as it can point
to it that you extract the current
rectory
you can get very busy with the stuff
i don't want you guys to worry any more
about
taro than we're going to make some cards
later on right now your unpacking at
fifteen examples
so let's go ahead and ncd into
cd examples
and one fifty thing is from these
commands we try to expand them
there's more support samples
files and directories there's that
examples that stop
it knew that something here cd that i
was looking for only directories
so it's not a complete with anything
other than full-version directories
planning to seek a mandate alb
it's getting nor all the other voices
out there in that direction
but we going to go into examples
and will do analyst at selling its
initial allot of files here
try to create a little temple working
area that's got halts works of data
sort of israel clovis just quick made up
stuff
just meant to be simple
and we want to start looking at this
stuff and see how it's put together
but reported that
can have a sense of the size of things
the last command iran was ls rationale
for a long listing and it's giving us
this column of numbers
rate in the middle here
that's our filesize
if we had a dash h to that
facility report
it's going to show you
in quite a bit small
in k
which is kilobytes if it's all the
bigger
amber megabytes
cheaper gigabytes
and i haven't worked with too many
terrified files person that will be
so here's a fifty megabyte file
here's a four hundred and seven k file
so you can see how big things are
and there's actually away on the system
to open up files in the polls are
petition
you catholics and say
please open up this file pick an
application for me that you think is the
best or my preferred one
on the mac that
commanders called open
on one x date
headed away a little bit and i have to
keep looking up because i would still
get
a little bit funny and you arthur you're
making a list later honors for members
it's x
deep g dash open
when the files in here it is called
field procedure
manual
may two thousand levin dot pbf
so this is a p_b_s_ documentary crap
from nl website
some of you might be familiar with it
and you can view this exit
deje dash open
and should pop up
x d g
dash open
field procedures manual
is the nice thing about
the command-line tools
especially when she was that they often
recommend
i think you really meant to run for the
command
they know of a little bit about that
to protect that outcomes of document
browser wikipedia bennett
you're certain to learn
to write scripts
at the end of your script you produced
by the pbf document and you want to
bring it up in a browser
your programs you great can call this
command
and say hey opening a spinal block with
a three and preventing
what is really nice if you are you doing
long-running scripts we sometimes around
here
right stuff to fix it
maybe even a day or two to run
and if you sit there and watch a
computer for a day or two for your
current finishing a crazy
but it's at the end of props up the end
result
results as you go
i picked this document particular
because we're gonna
see this
throughout
and if you're taking
sakte hai certification class
you've got a lot of pay attention to
this
this is the no manual
how to go out into high traffic surveys
so if you want to see what would know
what things it takes
to go out and survey the ocean
this is a key document to have
in hand even if you're not doing had
graphic surveys yourself if you do
another kind of wanting to raise
there's a lot of techniques in this
document missus howell
a big government organization had which
would be hard
to come up with uh... best practices
for them and so if you
you can use this is either a story
template for away with their back-burner
material
or the place to start from an adopt a
new procedure based on some new created
when we get into mort
detailed deaths of the said we're going
to go in iran actually look at some of
the entries
so you can do
patrolling
flew back to being wined and you can use
the url keys to admit
so you haven't unpacked this examples
said to you it's hard
you're states
space
he acts in the first time
inter
then see the into it when it's done
working
cv
space examples
next time
go up to that
expert at the efforts to see this
grief they're pressed for time
and now you have a field procedures
manual
please do if you get stuck
and ask for help
i think some uh... getting used to be
out of your stuff
and if you're waiting for us to feel
free to read about that documents
doesn't stuff in there
figuring lots of error messages about
timestamps
that's okay
when the prompt personal mission to
reach up and down
they sometimes lose their sense of time
if you look at that point it may be off
given our special
so you're says it's a plumber eight even
though it's a template for king state
don't worry about that if you get a
regular time it's not a big deal
you can visit the site
we can do the time out for him
and lecturer hutchings
okay
special
so you see you have this examples
directory you need to see the intern
since the deep space
examples
presenter
and now if you do in dallas that show
you'll see all the documents
fiji national thing
and you can type xti g dash open
a capital at
and probably get tubs of xti g
national been
and capital up
impressed habitable complete directions
and i want to make sure that you also
still procedure manual now at this point
in your career
at u_n_ eight rather than
somewhere in the middle of the summer
hydro course when you try to figure out
something
excellence is why didn't you read a
field procedures manual forever hint as
to what you're doing
this document it isn't always the ways
can be done here
some oppressors here have their own
taped on how to look at data and do
procedures
but it's really nice to have that
officially to be able to read
when you want a second opinion on how to
do something
or just another
approach on the same topic
so we need to go to sleep late night
i recommend opening up this document now
certain very
and we'll talk about why bags are excuse
will
that structure that's not
a good thing eric's people it's a
mistake
next topic is going to be using uh... a
command
it gets a little confusing in section
because we're using a thing called file
if they were talking about rank and file
on files
spinal is this clever thing
where they build up a database
of information about
while types
so it knows a little bit about
how does a p_b_s_ start it doesn't care
about the name of a file it cares about
the contents of the files of the lookin
therein
look at the plates enough i don't say
i think it's a what
took a sip e_d_s_
the first couple characters n_p_f_ file
actually have pbf right now
so we're gonna run file
so you actually use the name file
and then
on what
and if you've ever watched time we
talked about matching patterns
so we can say parle
star
for everything
let's go ahead and do that and it's
going to be
a lot of job
it burns when u talent
so with the file commands
i've actually done in
yet in this version of you go into but i
think the next first if you're going to
actually know about some more to be
formats
because i sat there and try to figure
out
how to identify that particular format
anna at database that has
so if you have any file format do you
want to have added
we can sit down and see if it's possible
to create definition file
that explains
house put together but for example like
a cause person rabble tvm
has about seven year a different
possible starting by combinations
i kinda gave up
right realized that said
we know it i'm not that motivated to go
create definition for
person that filed some of them were
paid enough that they conflict with
other definitions
so that was pretty hard but if you do
file star
you're gonna get a whole lot of
don't expect
much dot to make sense
anti-democrat back around this again
emina pipette to head so the vertical
bar
passes data from one command to the next
to me and
and ahead command
takes the first time lines analytical
otherwise page is gonna grab only the
first time lines and then it's going to
stop receiving care from filing norris
collectively to blank lines we got to
see this and all rerun the file
someone walk appearance
walk you through just a few of them so
you see them
so here is this quality
oh four seven nine a bunch of stuff
r_b_c_ s dot all but be easy to
so that was our compressed file
later him wildly if you need help
getting the file commands to work
you've done the file
space star
third going to stand in the first time
to happens
feel was jumped at the apparel
yet something that the last may not have
that vertical bar which is right back
stay still
and then head
it's always wise to put spaces in for
the shell between different things in
this case if you figure out that had and
the birth of our work
separate entities
there's times when they can't figure
that out
and it's in confusing errors
it doesn't work
when you have to find all the edge cases
on me and uh...
files are pipette
okay yet
energies a couple times yourselves a
blank lines
foresight player
inside player
second point one nine apparently at the
top man
you're seeing the same thing ending and
so we found this particular faction
returning working
phyllis just think if we could get some
of the stuff we have here
when you see data
that means it's awesome binary data and
didn't know what it was
ascii english text with control l_l_
flying terminators
uh... that means that sort of a coffee
for my while
with something if they did recognize
jpg image data at the picture
here we have a folder running a
directory
this is guide to ask you like this is an
ask you like three database that the
davissix lives in a file
here we have my delicious bookmarks that
i think the point of
free to play with
it didn't quite get that that was an
html document they thought it was an s
gml document text
if you ever start working with us gml
three very impressed block prosecuted
for it
we don't work with that stuff really
therefore my father was tossed text
really simple insure a very similar to
the asking which text
effort couldn't figure out their english
words in there
empty file
purchasers of them peace if he did touch
in some plumbing bill so empty
and then here
he didn't just tell us a p yet document
also calls the version of the ph dinner
that docking certainty
tennessee
we have g_p_s_ in here in the czech
different versions
a lot of us have to go see won't make
too much sense so hopefully things like
a pay you've run into the foreign you're
familiar with
what you're seeing so many times it by
the end of this course
you should be able to just found out
what they are without having think about
it
three of us here at this prop one d
r_b_c_ s data and said
i see is compressed
i'm not gonna look in there
feel like wasting the energy to go on
compressed this and can tell you
if you're the one do this you prolly
wanna under pressure data
we do
an ls dash l
star dot jeezy and star dot be easy to
you
we should list
for us all the files that are compressed
jeezy compression and easy to
compression
if the naming convention is held in this
so we've got four files that are
compressed
we've got three would be zip
easy to you
extensions
and even tell here
at this one is a different color that's
outside the
asi gyi file
it's got the executed set so it's less
as a program even know if you were in it
who knows what would happen
it's just a tad bit got flagged
incorrectly
there's two different commands
so each of those compression format is
on uncompressed commands
before please it to you
if you just type
the u_n_'s ian tab
stadiums that to you
and then we could say star dot be easy
to you
and i will go through
and uncompressed of easy to files
you could use a starter and it's just
looking to unzip isn't on
compressed would be easy to do
frank
will do that
and what uncompressed those three files
we move towards working
the next demand is going to be
g unzip
so we had
the unzip
teased or not
the the
hearing there
it's gonna be g unzip
stone dot
c
to at the end that finished you'll say
gee unzipped
star dot cheesy
now once more
so uncompressed really fast
so now please scroll back up that was
the commands looking for gps and easy to
use
mickey kantor again
it said i couldn't find anything
susan allen compressed
sin for example to take a look at
uh... zero four hit album
soloist at shell zero four
cabin you'll see that
there's no longer a dog easy to with the
ends up file
it's gone from being
three point seven m bytes two
ten megabytes
it's now much bigger
and we can run file night
so now we're in pile on the file
attach confused yet
and hit enter
and now it just says it's binary data
that i don't know anything about
plot sucks
you guys have his newly told us that
knew what i know this is
isn't actually assume rag ada from the
post of air
effective at the home
from two thousand eight
but we don't know that from the poly it
hasn't
what's going on
took couple commands we can do go look
at binary data if you're brave
that last command that we've seen before
look at files
some say it lasts
the report this is that peter command
that's running with him and page
if it sees binary data it's going try
and protect you from it
it's good show you as much as they can
and not
suritai blasts and our file
as they say
this may be binary
you might not like what you're gonna see
in a moment
do you want to continue
and we definitely want to see what's in
there
reply
everything and whites
steven on principle character so if
somebody read
that doesn't represent the character of
a place just data
and so there's no character to go with
it might be able smiley faces running
around
that's not so it's meant to be english
text
but there's things in here
that are
intact
and unfortunately we now have them
bush together
and it's not very much fun and that
there might be lost this stuff in it
who knows where it is in the file
and this is the part where you start
having with
well it's always augment that work
together
there's a command called strengths
that goes into data
and it finds all the human readable
thank you maria will be in quotes thing
eight might be
on the file
now don't hit enter
we do history arson there waiting for
lots of text to go home
worried that tightening and
british countries corporation moon
fibc does not mean water closet it means
wordcount
the same as the man page so hw
please do shot out to get stuck
it takes a lot of our patient
researching the patterns in owen to be
getting q one q control
c satara
did you tell us
space
store
dot be easy to
so you want to bus
this technology assessments and
therefore
and then pressed count
so then press enter
you'll sit it says
lucy desi say yes
anybody reach out
hit q to put out the pager
selfless
it's nice that we can look at the stuff
but we want to from western commanders
fifty kinney series
numbers spaces warmers
it's got more than four hundred regret
that i think you're worth
w_c_
the number of words and lines in a
accent rodents at the headquarters from
the results
today d_c_ word count the number of
words in line to bring to get back to
the runs command
so we're gonna get back
twenty one thousand twenty thousand
lines
renea twenty six thousand words
and a hundred and forty three thousand
characters
that's a lot of stuff to read
so we're gonna go ahead and do the same
thing but we're gonna pass it to you
back manhattan
visit here is the first time lines out
of
those trends that
before we had all that by a review
running around in the game
so now we have this thing that looks
like
it was meant for humans you can kinda
if you know what up
pete use e_ z_ equals zero means
you can actually read this and maybe get
something out of it
and if you start skimming through summit
barnard files
there's often paxton everything ground
out
you could actually pull out the g_p_s_
locations from the spinal
because they're in there as nema strings
as actual ascii text
city certificates for gta or g g l
in this file we'll actually find the
g_p_s_ strings
quickly look here worrying for all this
week they don't know what all the stuff
that is
blah blah blah
off the job
but down here
play second assessed looking like i can
actually read that
height zero two thousand eight
today to sea calm
day one of
summer heitor two thousand eight
so we know nothing about what this file
is but we now have something that we can
go ask it without
someone haiti the files that please
process that's you could dine
so walk around t common try to find
someone who knew whats
some writer two thousand eight was
figures and information on it
display you don't know anything about
the file format but you are not
something about it
you've got in there and figured out a
little bit
and use the power of these links tools
to dig into stuff that can be a little
scary
yeltsin happens may try something be
brave it isn't in my notes
pipette tellabs
we can see what and lots of the stuff
so this
t_g_a_ rate here
one of those g_p_s_ strengths
i want to show you plant called
which stands for general regular
expressions
right now don't worry about what a
regular expression is just know that
it's the search for patterns intact
and the simplest pattern is an exact
match
so we have added g_g_ a string they were
looking for
so we want to ask it go find as all the
d_g_a_ string
so we've basically got
japanese strings from are
dot all file
we're gonna pass out to this weird rec
program that you have just seen
indeed ever really banking with
and what it wanted
to only returned to us the g_g_ a string
to come from a g_p_s_
and if you get banner
bc a whole piles of g_p_s_ strings that
in stockton that's fine
based on this you can actually go wait a
little bit echoed
without revealing the binary to plot the
ship track
for this file
sis pretty cool because we've
ticket buyer datafile we don't even know
how to parse binary deal yet
and we grab the g_p_s_ formats
if you really had to
you could use by hand flew into an
attack senator
and if you look in here
we actually looks like we might have
some ordnance
so we've got
north and west in here
you have to figure out is a spot longer
how to make a lot long
which you're on your way to being able
to parse g_p_s_ data funds
sword fighting
so if we have this file
i've had to go back to this
wanted everything in here
go back to this j paid to rehab so we
had some image
the picture of some sort
what it says here
is that it's a checked bag in his death
and there's lots of formats of in
images theirs
gaf sergey s
there's p_n_g_ ease
there's a good fifty or sixty
commonly used in this format
let's see what else is in there
we can use that grep command
phil dupont store
the vertical bar for the fight
requisite research for some taxed
and research for the word units
it's possible that images might have
something else in them
but here
we've actually gone and aspect and came
back with a tent
anything about texas in some of the
marcio tests mean uh... inside them
isn't that a whole bunch uh...
geospatial information about
where that
ticket is on the world from some
image some sort
in this case i know it's raster uh...
love that name
this is busy working some patch of the
air
that's great
now we have two images but we know very
little about them
how many pixel are they
are they located within your recovery
notes on them
really don't know too much about them
so let's go and learn some put commands
to deal with at least because i think
images are fun because we get to see
stuff pretty quickly
and if i could get bass enough
before you leave today we're gonna see a
pretty cool picture from
was the last couple days
first command ran into you
is called the ten if i and thus the part
of a package called image magic
so it's gonna be identified
and then
move ahead
and be lazy n-type star dot jpg and
start dot yet
and one thing to realize
j peg images off and also have milky in
their extension
people have different ways of writing it
these things are just hates
so that means they can also be stored at
whatever
would then have a hard time
but having things in a consistent
commission makes it easy
danner
yucky doesn't look great but
from here down
these are warnings from the text file
about tags that image magic didn't know
about
we don't care
grumpy having a bad day we care about
when it work
mobile seeing here is
vijay bhai came back and it gave the
image size so it's twelve thousand five
thousand pixels
it's an eight-day color image
if you don't know how to read that as an
a_p_ color image that used to it
this trip here
it's a lot bigger it's thirty two
thousand pixels by twelve hundred pixels
and it's an eight-day freescale
so we now know a little bit more
that's that's great but we don't
actually know
too much about it
better if you could see it
we would have been nice if you could
take a look at a picture for help and
just see text about it
so there's a really nice command call
display
at least a display star dot
jpg and start dot test
it's going to pop up on our screen
pictures that we used to photoshop and
a tool called the camp
used a final open and you'll find some
stuff
this way
you can write a script is doing
something it produces an indigenous
process work rather from a camera some
around the world
and it will end his display
soviet display
you're now looking out
the top of the hwy
mister shipp that a good number of
secom folks are on right now open the
arctic
and this picture is from
september twelfth
so yesterday
and now looking out
the aloft han
and up top
intact britain into the picture
they've got to take the time
where they were here temperature and
wind speed exciter setter
if you get the space bar
it's gonna work for a second and receive
something that's kinda weird looking
this actually is some nice geologic data
this is a polite are dataset
airborne laser looking down from a plane
brewing around us
that no one survey invite our
you have to be unilateral rabin eyes
what might be in here
and why and what we've done
you get used to that we're going to be
releasing the picture and you go out for
an hour so somebody
if yukio
you've got your terminal
image magic is the set of tools
you'll not find a command called image
magic
you'll find
identifying
and is one of them
photo options and display
image that has a lot of commands
some of them are very strange
mob reply
capture weapons
you get a simple commands to be able to
to change images you can also kemper
images that have a nice cover commands
of someone ask you for a j faggot etc
you can quickly view from the pan am one
inmate
response
let's take another look at
some more tools and we're gonna come
back image magic word he used a lot
ran a comeback was next to a marine even
more
and his tools called g down
that year spatial data abstraction
library
and they have a tool called g dot info
judo info
a great program that works on a lot of
different image formats especially if
they're geospatial ian able
it can tell us about files that have
location them solicit a car he lied to
me
so he had started to govern eleven
tonight tab
so there's r_j_ page from the healing
enter for geo info
it's gonna scroll off the screen which
is
will back up here take a quick peek at
what's in here
so here in the command and affect comes
all the output
it told us that it's using
this particular driver it's very wordy
mixed tell us everything of thinking
it told us how big the picture is right
here
the court is estimates
so didn't know what quarter system with
the news
but the clothing is inside the
meditative section
innocent where mandate is actually
exciting
but the fact that many of you may
make their own future one minute here
there's these things called except tags
in tibet
it that picture actually knows where it
is spatially
w to exit g_p_s_ latitude longitude
and so you can see that the latches
markdowns
eighty one degrees forty minutes twenty
four seconds more
and one twenty six forty seven
so that's the way up in the arctic
so it wasn't too surprising that we saw
pictures of myself that window
their way up there
and to give you our years of might not
be any ice
and it goes during tells you about the
various bands
to have a color image you have a hearty
n_b_c_ of three bands
will get more into that as we go through
images
so that worked pretty well
and we got back this point
that picture was taken at that
particular axa morning on the air
what's called the bet you can't because
that you tip was actually
maps to uh... an area of your not just a
point
so that you know info
amit have
which when looking for something for the
world laughs with each one one
two nine six
five-year hill shade
if u
workaround noel i feel sort of recognize
their survey number pattern
the had record survey with some number
after it
which doesn't really tell you too much
of them is the sequence of service
so do the geo info on our health shape
and to get back a little bit more
bridging tiff is a little bit more
focused on
giving you geospatial information
if the court is just in case
you get this huge block of stuff
and this tells you it's a tear the
g_s_a_ poorer
datum
with ticknor
shape of the earth
those with units are apparent agrees
it tells you what this thing called
u_p_s_ chico's
you'll see the throughout
the semester
these codes if you know that u_p_s_
chico for something you know the
projection that sam
as a whole database of these
epic and down here to the corner
coordinates
this tells you the bounding box that
that this images in
so if you
where i have a map
this tells you
those poor poor locations
and if you drew the earth
what a map in there and
pasted that image on top of allocation
that's workers
so this file knows exactly where it is
not here
geo info
it's one one
had to have a blessed times
so the first to be a tablet doesn't want
to show you anymore unless they can
exactly matching have a couple times
that is for sure in the options
and you can have a live more
so you want to get to you
anytime
gives you a bit more heat up couple
times to get this list
and here you're looking for an
underscore make the next character
so now you see it saying
about three options
the earlier age one one and i need to
take
team
is next here if you want some press two
heat up again
a couple times
so gives you a list
he picked it up
see how he had twice facet that shows
you a list
you know that two options eighty to
underscore a dash in the only one is the
state lawmakers or
so shift
and nike
the shifts
now pressed her
now presenter
and now you have the whole into and you
can use the scroll wheel on the mouse to
scroll back up
ed ever you're feeling like
you know your head hangs in your your
you're all caught up
and over the summer three topic you keep
your waiting on something in your head
you can read them and pages on in these
things before
you're the man web browser and just we
had a little bit it's it's well worth
the time to it
invest in these things
and the next epic has been a wood stick
three a script
they were going up five minutes
so i'm gonna walk through it don't worry
about following along
i'm gonna preeti max
and the cradle script and run it
and then next time on thursday
will start reading a script as your his
commands you go to local while that if
you have a new set of data
you can rerun always commands on it as
you go
so the keeping your member is where
michelle worth keeping track of stuff
and if i want to see what i've been
doing
i can type history
as any do number blessed with a number
if the item
a key member
bands comment before he sits there
banging on those numbers and we run it
so we can say
i wanna rerun the display command means
number
for here thirty two
aka dues-paying burden to you
and i'll see the picture
what are you now as i'm in trying grab a
couple cummins together
and put them into
a hollow victory run
because these are just in your history
and if u
tonight
gets in the history of the someone else
and have it work
so many go ahead and run
he knew the max
the also he max is all keyboard
shortcuts and you don't get
at all really unless you know the
keyboard shortcut to get help
used to be very frustrating
university max for the last few years
so you guys all have a big leg up on
these long-time hits
if you get
menu options
and i'll tell you the keyboard shortcut
on the right as you go
control
x control applicant file but what this
is the maze for now i'm workin the
keyboard shortcuts as we go later
from a visit in the file
it doesn't really know directories
so i want to go and select this floor
arrow next to browse through the folders
but the downtown now is showing me that
the folders just like you look at most
while tools
summer findarticles directory
which is right here
or click on that
nam inside examples
i'm in a minute my dash peretz
dot at sage
later on we'll explain
wire might mean something like that
manhattan okay
and now it's carrying a blank page which
isn't very helpful
yep no worries force
which is my job to do you guys uh...
comes through it
we are simple commands
preview ako
this is different from the answer will
use that just to get started
to echo
hello
script
and i'm gonna go out
throughout safety if i go back to
terminal
ls dash l
now if i do a dash
tns there sort by time
and ash are the reverse order
you'll certainly sees a minute he tell
you what i'm doing everything written
hopefully he'll fix him up slowly
and what this will do a quick everything
in in sort order for time in the most
recent thing will be at the bottom
there's a lot of files that there is
growing by both the bottom
is my skirt dot its age
now it's not showing up at executed wolf
we don't have to worry about that right
now there is a command to run shell
scripts
hulu second
but i can't i bless and my i dash
correct
and if you take a look at up com
international we thank you
and then i can say source
mine dash prints
and this is going to run all the
commands in that file
as if you type in the consul
and he writes a very exciting hello from
my script
and with that
i think we're leaving here for today
and we'll get back into this on thursday
watching was writing a script
i think you might try to download some
images from the healy
and make a little movie
if you guys want to animation of the hwy
driving around the ice will give gotta
go on thursday
and we'll get some action on the screen
some visual contactor